<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MK's Blog</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on MK's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 08:39:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Monthly Todo List Using Vimwiki</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/simple-cli-monthly-todo-list-using-vimwiki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 08:39:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/simple-cli-monthly-todo-list-using-vimwiki/</guid><description>Introduction I use Loop Habit Tracker as a reminder for daily to do checklist.
I wanted to implement something similar for tracking monthly todo list. But I was too lazy to implement an android app or fork and modify Loop Habit Tracker.
And running a webserver on a Single Board Computer (Orange Pi 4B) seemed like a bad idea as it constantly hogs resources.
So I decided to write a simple bash script to create a monthly todo checklist.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Android Apps</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/recommended-android-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 13:09:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/recommended-android-apps/</guid><description>GnuCash GnuCash is the best expense tracking android app in my opinion, it even lets you automatically export your transactions to Dropbox, which allows you write an alert microservice to fetch the GnuCash Export Book from Dropbox and send an alert when you exceed the set budget for a month or build your own Personal Recon System (I will write another detailed article about the endless possibilities). The only downside is that you&amp;rsquo;re expected to log every single transaction manually (Been doing this for over 2 years now).</description></item><item><title>AWS Step Patterns</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/aws-step-patterns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 13:14:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/aws-step-patterns/</guid><description>Introduction This article will talk about few of the most frequently used patterns in AWS Step. It assumes that you are familiar with AWS Step, if you want to learn about it, I suggest creating an AWS account and check out the example blueprint state machine definitions available or reading this
AWS Step Patterns Chunked Iterator Consider this problem
A CRM tool is used by sales team (Pipedrive) needs new data from Redshift (Data Warehouse) once a day, to do this you can use Pipedrive API&amp;rsquo;s to Create or Update Deals.</description></item><item><title>Agni Siragugal Foreward</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/agni-siragugal-foreward/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:37:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/agni-siragugal-foreward/</guid><description>அக்னி சிறகுகள் தமிழ் பதிப்பிற்காக எழுதப்பட்டது
தமிழக மக்களுக்கு அக்னி சிறகுகள் என்னுடயை சுய சரிதத்தை படிக்க ஆரம்பிக்கும் முன்பு உங்கள் ஒவ்வொருவர் மனத்திலும் ஏன் ஒரு தமிழ் மகன் தன்னுடைய சுய சரிதத்தை ஆங்கிலத்தில் எழுது அதை இன்னொருவர் தமிழில் மொழி பெயர்க்க வேண்டும் என்ற வினா தோன்றும்
கடந்த ஐம்பது ஆண்டுகளாக படித்து பனி செய்தது பனி செய்து கேட்டிருப்பது எல்லாவற்றிலும் ஆங்கில மொழி நுழையந்துவிட்டது. இதனால் சுய சரிதா ஆதாரங்கள் பலர் குறைந்த நேரத்தில் ஆங்கிலத்தில் உருவாகும் நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.
ஏன் நண்பர் அருண் திவாரி என்னுடைய சுய சரிதத்தை நான் புத்தகமாக என்னுடன் ஆங்கிலம் மூலம் ஒத்துழைக்க முடிந்தது.</description></item><item><title>Language Learning Tool - Califone Cardmaster</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/language-learning-tool-califone-cardmaster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:51:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/language-learning-tool-califone-cardmaster/</guid><description>To create a language learning android app that resembles this machine with multiple language pack cards. There should be pre-recorded cards that can be used to learn pronunciation of words. And cards that students can use on the other side. A percentage match of the audio should be shown after student&amp;rsquo;s attempt
Watch the video for more context</description></item><item><title>DAG Workflow Using AWS Step Functions and AWS Lambda</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/dag-workflow-using-aws-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 04:01:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/dag-workflow-using-aws-step/</guid><description>At Instamojo, we use Amazon Redshift as the data warehouse.
A typical requirement for analytics team is to aggregate new data from multiple source tables (say raw events) that can later be used in BI tools, dashboards, charts or other machine learning jobs.
For the sake of simplicity, let&amp;rsquo;s assume these are the aggregate operations performed
$$ f = MIN(x) $$
$$ f = MAX(x) $$
$$ f = COUNT(x) $$</description></item><item><title>Puzzle: Triangle in a Square Defined by Arcs</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/puzzle-triangle-in-a-square-defined-by-arcs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 20:22:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/puzzle-triangle-in-a-square-defined-by-arcs/</guid><description>Question Solving it using GeoGebra Area of the triange is $$0.04 x^2$$ where $$x$$ is the length of the side of the square.
Solving it without GeoGebra Let the Quarter Circle ACD be $$C_1$$
Let the Semi Circle with Diameter along AB be $$C_2$$
Let the Semi Circle with Diameter along BC be $$C_3$$
$$ C_1: x^2 + y^2 = 1 $$
$$ C_2: (x-0.5)^2 + (y-1)^2 = 0.25 $$</description></item><item><title>My Origami Collection</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/my-origami-collection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 19:21:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/posts/my-origami-collection/</guid><description>I re-create the paper structures posted by Neospica Paper Structures youtube channel.
Column miura paraboloid Paper Folding origami Twisted Column Paper Lamp Fold Folding Cup Intersecting Patterns</description></item><item><title>Site Notice</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/site-notice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:46:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/site-notice/</guid><description>Code for this can be found on Github. Blog generated with Hugo.
This blog&amp;rsquo;s theme is a fork of Natrium theme.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:41:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mmuthukrishna.github.io/blog/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m M.Muthukrishna, a software developer currently working for Instamojo. I graduated from PES University in 2019.
You can find my resume here</description></item></channel></rss>